Loved for being unique. Hated for being different.
Wilde is a drama, history film directed by Brian Gilbert.
Oscar Wilde is a married playwright who has occasionally
indulged his weakness for male suitors.
After much toil, Wilde debuts 'The Importance of Being Earnest' in London, and a chat at the
theatre with Lord Alfred 'Bosie' Douglas leads to a full-fledged romance.
However, this affair leads to a legal dispute with Lord Alfred's oppressive father, the
Marquess of Queensberry, and, given the local anti-gay laws, Wilde is jailed.
Wilde's vast intellect helps him survive until he regains his freedom.
Oscar Wilde, played by Stephen Fry.
Lord Alfred 'Bosie' Douglas, played by Jude Law.
Lady Speranza Wilde, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Constance Lloyd Wilde, played by Jennifer Ehle.
Lady Queensberry, played by Gemma Jones.
Lady Mount-Temple, played by Judy Parfitt.
Wilde is a 1997 British biographical romantic
drama film directed by Brian Gilbert.
The screenplay, written by Julian Mitchell, is based on
Richard Ellmann's 1987 biography of Oscar Wilde.
It stars Stephen Fry in the title role, with Jude Law, Vanessa Redgrave, Jennifer Ehle, Gemma Jones,
Judy Parfitt, Michael Sheen, Zoë Wanamaker, and Tom Wilkinson in supporting roles.
The film premiered at the 54th Venice International Film Festival on 1 September 1997, and was
theatrically released in the United Kingdom on 17 October 1997, by PolyGram Filmed Entertainment.
It was praised for the performances of the cast, particularly that of Fry, who received
critical acclaim and a Best Actor nomination at the 56th Golden Globe Awards.
Ehle and Wanamaker were both nominated for Best Actress in a
Supporting Role at the 51st British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of prison, coming out,
london, england, wife, biography.
The tone is emotional.